{"tossups": [{"question": "This poet claimed that \"birth was a disease and Christopher and I invented the cure\" in \"O Ye Tongues\", a sequence of poems based on Christopher Smart's \"Jubilate Agno\". The line \"I have gone out, a possessed witch\" opens a poem by this author whose three stanzas end with the claim \"I have been\" the title thing. This student of W.D. Snodgrass wrote a poem which asks her daughter \"how do you grow?\" and tells her \"you are too many to eat\", while the lines \"Whether you are pretty or not, I outlive you, bend down my strange face to yours and forgive you\" conclude a poem addressed to her father. This poet wrote (*) \"Her Kind\", \"Little Girl, My String Bean, My Lovely Woman\", and \"All My Pretty Ones\". For 10 points, name this author of To Bedlam and Part Way Back and The Awful Rowing Toward God, who, like her friend Sylvia Plath, was a suicidal female Confessional poet.", "answer": "Anne Sexton ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Anne <b><u>Sexton</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Anne Sexton", "Sexton"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "According to the Witten effect, any grand unified theory which does NOT show this phenomenon has dyons with only integer charges. The interaction of scalar fields with the instanton field causes this phenomenon as part of the Affleck-Dine mechanism. When this phenomenon does NOT occur, the areas of the unitarity triangles vanish. Along with thermal disequilibrium and violation of the baryon number, this phenomenon is one of the conditions required for (*) baryogenesis according to the Sakharov conditions. Complex phases in the CKM matrix allow for this phenomenon. In local and Lorentz-invariant quantum field theories, this phenomenon necessitates a flipping of the time-reversal symmetry. The indirect form of this phenomenon was originally discovered in the decay of neutral kaons by James Cronin and Val Fitch. For 10 points, name this phenomenon in which the product of charge conjugation and parity symmetry are broken by some process.", "answer": "CP violation [or charge conjugation and parity until \"charge conjugation\" is read] ", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>CP</u></b> violation [or <b><u>charge conjugation</u></b> or <b><u>parity</u></b> until \"charge conjugation\" is read]", "acceptable": ["CP violation", "CP", "charge conjugation", "parity"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This philosopher put forth eight principles for determining the international order in a book that envisages a world in which the evils of history no longer occur, called a \"realistic utopia.\" This philosopher called political theories that depend on compliant actors and favorable social conditions \"ideal theory.\" This philosopher describe a method by which, through adjusting one's general principles so that they mutually support one another, one can arrive at a state of (*) \"reflective equilibrium.\" The ideas of this author of The Law of Peoples prompted Robert Nozick to write Anarchy, State, and Utopia. He used a thought experiment in which parties design a society without knowing their status, due to a \"veil of ignorance,\" to argue that society should work to benefit the most disadvantaged. For 10 points, name this author of A Theory of Justice.", "answer": "John Rawls", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>John Rawls</u></b>", "acceptable": ["John Rawls", "John Rawls"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Since three of the four branches of the Austronesian language family are exclusive to this island, it is believed to be that family's homeland. Mark Moskowitz studied the odd practice of stripping at funerals on this island. Apart from the Kavalan tribe, tribes of aboriginal plains-dwellers have not been recognized on this island, though they still typically support the Pan-Blue Coalition. Major fault lines caused the 1999 921 earthquake on this island, where the formerly Dutch fort Zeelandia is located. The (*) Portuguese named this island for its beauty and named a group of islands to the west after their fisherman. The Pescadores are located west of this island, where a giant New Year's fireworks show takes place at a tower with 101 floors. For 10 points, name this island formerly known as Formosa, which contains most of the Republic of China.", "answer": "Taiwan [or Isla Formosa until \"Formosa\" is read] ", "category": "Geography", "subcategory": "Geography", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Taiwan</u></b> [or <b><u>Isla Formosa</u></b> until \"Formosa\" is read]", "acceptable": ["Taiwan", "Taiwan", "Isla Formosa"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "John Chester Miller's authoritative biography of this man called him a \"Pioneer in Propaganda\" and he took the alias \"Candidus\" in one publication. While a clerk, this man managed to get a hold of correspondence written to Thomas Whatley and publicized them in the Hutchinson Letters Affair. This man was blamed by Francis Bernard for the lynching of Andrew Oliver, though that act was actually performed by the Loyal Nine. This man, who was called the \"last of the Puritans\" by Edward Everett, drafted a circular letter that stated the (*) Townshend Acts were illegitimate because of a separation by an \"ocean of a thousand leagues\". A longtime ally of James Otis, this man famously stated \"this meeting can do nothing further to save the country\" to end a gathering at the Old South Meeting House, after which a group of men dressed as Mohawks boarded the Dartmouth. For 10 points, name this maltster and leader of the Sons of Liberty who organized the Boston Tea Party.", "answer": "Samuel Adams [prompt on \"Adams\"] ", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Samuel Adams</u></b> [prompt on <u>Adams</u>]", "acceptable": ["Samuel Adams", "Samuel Adams"], "promptable": ["Adams"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one film, this character wears a red t-shirt with a fake six pack-abs design and destroys a security camera before saying, \"Now I am alone.\" In a Frank Zeffirelli film, after this character pretends to nearly drop a sword, a shot reverse shot sequence shows him winking at his mother. A title filmic character of this name who visits a New York hotel-slash-corporate HQ is played by Ethan Hawke. In a fourth film, the camera slowly zooms out from this character in the snow as he gives a speech inspired by \"the (*) imminent death of twenty thousand men.\" In that 1996 film, he taps a one-way mirror with a knife in an empty ballroom and dismisses a lover played by Kate Winslet. For 10 points, name this theatrical character filmed by Kenneth Branagh starring Kenneth Branagh, who, according to the preface of a 1948 Laurence Olivier filming, shows the \"tragedy of a man who could not make up his mind.\"", "answer": "Prince Hamlet of Denmark [do not accept \"King Hamlet\"] ", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Prince Hamlet of Denmark</u></b> [do not accept \"King Hamlet\"]", "acceptable": ["Prince Hamlet of Denmark", "Prince Hamlet of Denmark"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character in this play claims to have written a novel in which \"the good ended happily, and the bad unhappily\" because \"that is what Fiction means\". In its penultimate line, a character is accused by his aunt of \"displaying signs of triviality\". One character in this play claims that an aunt in Tunbridge Wells gave him a suspiciously-inscribed cigarette case, while another invents an (*) invalid friend living in the country who he uses to get out of social engagements in a practice called \"Bunburying\". At the end of this play, Dr. Chasuble pairs up with Miss Prism, who reveals that she had left a main character in a handbag in Victoria Station. For 10 points, name this play in which the unusual desires of Cecily Cardew and Gwendolen Fairfax are satisfied, an Oscar Wilde play in which Algernon Moncrieff and Jack Worthing both adopt the title name. ", "answer": "The Importance of Being Earnest ", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Importance of Being Earnest</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Importance of Being Earnest", "Importance of Being Earnest"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The category of these entities contains a faithful functor to the category of sets that has no right adjoint, but whose left adjoint associates a \"free\" one of these entities to its basis set. If they contain no non-identity elements that have finite order, they are called torsion-free, and the sum of two homomorphisms between two of these entities is also a homomorphism. The fundamental theorem of these structures states that finitely-generated ones can be decomposed into a direct sum of (*) cyclic groups with prime-power order. The centralizers of these entities are equivalent to these entities in their entirety, and the Cayley tables for these entities are symmetric. A ring whose nonzero elements form one of these entities under multiplication is a field. For 10 points, name these groups in which the order of the operation doesn't matter.", "answer": "abelian groups [prompt on commutative groups; prompt on partial answers until \"groups\" is read", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>abelian groups [prompt on commutative groups; prompt on partial answers until \"groups\" is read</u></b>", "acceptable": ["abelian groups [prompt on commutative groups; prompt on partial answers until \"groups\" is read", "abelian groups [prompt on commutative groups; prompt on partial answers until \"groups\" is read"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One king of this name wrote the semi-autobiographical \"King's Book\" about his eighteen-year foreign detainment during which he had led troops against his kingdom's armies in France. One king of this name had a birthmark that led to his nickname \"the fiery face\" and was the owner of the massive bombard Mons Meg. The only two British kings of this name not to start their reign in regency include (*) one whose premature retreat at his final defeat earned him the nickname \"the shit\", and the fourth king of this name, who honoured the Auld Alliance and died at the Battle of Flodden Field. The sixth king of this name also became known as the first of his name in England after the death of Elizabeth I. For 10 points, name this common first name of the Stuart kings of Scotland.", "answer": "James [or Seamus]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>James</u></b> [or <b><u>Seamus</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["James", "James", "Seamus"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Nikolai Malko's 1932 performance of a piece by this composer in London helped revive the popularity of that piece's original version. A rondo in the form A, B, A, B, C, A, D, A is used in the final movement of a suite by this composer, the first movement from which uses a pentatonic scale and alternates between 5/4 and 6/4 time. A movement from that suite by this composer evokes bells from a structure planned to be built by Viktor (*) Hartmann.  Leopold Stokowski removed a \"fanfare\" depicting a dark god in his 1940 arrangement one of this composer's pieces; that piece depicts a witches' sabbath on St. John's Eve. Maurice Ravel orchestrated a suite by this composer which includes the movement \"The Great Gate of Kiev.\" For 10 points, name this composer of Night on Bald Mountain and Pictures at an Exhibition.", "answer": "Modest Mussorgsky ", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Modest <b><u>Mussorgsky</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Modest Mussorgsky", "Mussorgsky"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This process titles a discourse that defines a \"stricken\" civilization as one that closes its eyes to its problems and a \"dying\" one that uses principles for trickery and deceit. People perpetrating this process have a \"Nero Complex\" according to a book by Albert Memmi. In an essay that closes by examining sati, the social group which is outside of the hegemonic power structure resulting from this process is termed the Subaltern. The reversal of this process' effects on the (*) mind is the objective of an essay that argues for the use of the Gikuyu language instead of English and was written by Ngugi wa Thiong'o. Gayatri Spivak is a theorist about the aftermath of this process, the dehumanization and racism resulting from which are analysed in Black Skin, White Masks by Frantz Fanon. For 10 points, name this frequently imperialistic process by which people settle new land.", "answer": "colonization [accept colonialism or anything involving colonies; prompt on \"imperialism\"] ", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>colonization</u></b> [accept <b><u>colonialism</u></b> or <b><u>anything involving colonies</u></b>; prompt on <u>imperialism</u>]", "acceptable": ["colonization", "colonization", "colonialism", "anything involving colonies"], "promptable": ["imperialism"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An attempt to capture this creature is shown on the left of the Ardre VIII stone. An animal known as the \"Sky-Bellower\" is killed before going on a trip to slay this creature. After slaying this creature, one character takes nine steps before falling dead. An enchanter makes his drinking-horn impossible to finish after using magic to turn this creature into a grey (*) cat, which is why the cat was so heavy that one hero could barely lift if off the floor. An ox head is used to bait this creature by a hero who attempts to kill it with a hammer. This sibling of a giant wolf and the goddess Hel poisons the sea and sky at the end of the world. For 10 points, name this creature which is killed by and kills Thor at Ragnarok, a giant Norse snake that circles the world.", "answer": "Jormungandr [or the Midgard Serpent; World Serpent; or obvious equivalents] ", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Jormungandr</u></b> [or the <b><u>Midgard Serpent</u></b>; World Serpent; or <b><u>obvious equivalents</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Jormungandr", "Jormungandr", "Midgard Serpent", "obvious equivalents"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An author with this last name wrote a novel whose hyperpatriotic protagonist argues with the soldier Wolfgang Buck and makes a political alliance with his nemesis Napoleon Fischer. Another author of this surname spent sixteen years \"transforming myth into flesh\" in the form of a four-part novel about a man who is exiled to Egypt, where he serves as Akhenaten's steward. The author of Man of Straw shares this surname with the creator of the doomed child Echo Nepomuk and a character who uses an (*) \"H, E, A, E, E-flat\" motif to represent a woman called \"Hetaera Esmeralda\". That author with this surname wrote Joseph and his Brothers and a novel narrated by Serenus Zeitblom in which the composer of Apocalypsis cum Figuris voluntarily contracts syphilis to increase his artistic output. For 10 points, give the surname shared by Heinrich and his brother, Doktor Faustus author Thomas.", "answer": "the Mann family [or Heinrich Mann; or Thomas Mann]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "the <b><u>Mann family</u></b> [or <b><u>Heinrich Mann</u></b>; or <b><u>Thomas Mann</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["the Mann family", "Mann family", "Heinrich Mann", "Thomas Mann"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "It's not pH, but a mineral redox buffer is used to constrain this quantity for oxygen in a rock system, and in such an analysis the log of this quantity is plotted against temperature for each component of the rock. It's not heat, but in the McKay et al approach this quantity times its namesake capacity is equal to the concentration. In a high-pressure VLE, the equation for this quantity is modified with the Poynting correction factor. It doesn't appear in Raoult's law, but this quantity for a component is equal to its (*) mole fraction times its total by the Lewis-Randall rule. This quantity is equal to its standard form times the exponential of the difference of the current and standard chemical potential over RT. At a given chemical potential, this quantity is equal to the pressure for an ideal gas. For 10 points, name this quantity which gives the tendency of a molecule to escape a particular phase.", "answer": "fugacity", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>fugacity</u></b>", "acceptable": ["fugacity", "fugacity"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The paiza was a pass that certified that a holder of this title had granted the possessor tax exemption. A ruler with this title ordered the construction of a silver tree with four serpents as its roots for a fountain in a capital city visited by William of Rubruck. Decrees issued known as yarlighs were issued by holders of this title, many of whom expanded the yam route system. John the Hungarian was an ambassador between one holder of this title and Louis IX. One of this title's holders ordered the destruction of (*) Alamut, the base of the Assassins. The kurultai elected holders of this position, one of whom created a secret law code called the Yassa. A ruler with this title supposedly turned a river black with ink when he sacked Baghdad in 1258. For 10 points, identify this title held by numerous Karakorum-based Mongolian rulers, such as Hulagu and Genghis.", "answer": "khan of the Mongols [or qaghan; or khan or qaghan of any of the convoluted divisions of the Mongol empire, such as Khan of the Golden Horde, Great Khan, the il-Khan; prompt on anything like \"leader of the Mongols\"] ", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>khan of the Mongols</u></b> [or <b><u>qaghan</u></b>; or <b><u>khan</u></b> or <b><u>qaghan of any of the convoluted divisions of the Mongol empire, such as Khan of the Golden Horde, Great Khan, the il-Khan</u></b>; prompt on <u>anything like \"leader of the Mongols</u>]", "acceptable": ["khan of the Mongols", "khan of the Mongols", "qaghan", "khan", "qaghan of any of the convoluted divisions of the Mongol empire, such as Khan of the Golden Horde, Great Khan, the il-Khan"], "promptable": ["anything like \"leader of the Mongols"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Police in this country banned an art show poster depicting a white nude on a pure orange background. Because an artist from this country disliked \"sugary ballet and dancing on points,\" he frequently painted crude scenes of nude dancers, including one showing a defiance of Moses. A saxophonist leans in to play his instrument as a woman with pink ostrich feathers raises her hand in a painting from this country that shows a veteran with two wooden legs begging at the left. The painters of the (*) Dance Around the Golden Calf and the Metropolis Triptych were from this non-Swiss country, where a watercolor showing several birds connected to a hand-crank was declared \"degenerate art.\" For 10 points, name this home country of Otto Dix and Die Br\u00c3\u00bccke, where the Nazis attempted to purge modern art.", "answer": "Germany [or the Third Reich; or the German Empire; or the Weimar Republic] ", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Germany</u></b> [or the <b><u>Third Reich</u></b>; or the <b><u>German Empire</u></b>; or the <b><u>Weimar Republic</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Germany", "Germany", "Third Reich", "German Empire", "Weimar Republic"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A crisis that threatened these two countries' alliance began when a steamship was sent to overturn the provisions of the Peace of Westphalia governing the Scheldt. During the War of the Polish Succession, one of these two countries seized the duchy of the spouse of the other country's ruler; that spouse was compensated with Tuscany. These two countries allied in response to the Westminster Convention but lost at the Battle of (*) Rossbach to Frederick the Great. These two countries became allied in the 1756 Diplomatic Revolution and fought as allies in the Seven Years' War. A bride in a diplomatic marriage between these two countries was Marie Antoinette. For 10 points, name these two countries ruled by the Habsburgs from the Schonbrunn Palace and the Bourbons from Versailles.", "answer": "France and Austria [or Kingdom of France and the Holy Roman Empire; or France and the Habsburg Monarchy/Empire before \"Habsburg\" is read; do not accept or prompt on \"Austria-Hungary\" for Austria] ", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>France and Austria</u></b> [or <b><u>Kingdom of France</u></b> or the <b><u>Holy Roman Empire</u></b>; or <b><u>France</u></b> or the <b><u>Habsburg Monarchy/Empire</u></b> before \"Habsburg\" is read; do not accept or prompt on \"Austria-Hungary\" for Austria\"]", "acceptable": ["France and Austria", "France and Austria", "Kingdom of France", "Holy Roman Empire", "France", "Habsburg Monarchy/Empire"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": ["Austria-Hungary\" for Austria"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In 1 Kings 13, one of these creatures stands by the corpse of a nameless \"disobedient prophet\" to show God's displeasure during the reign of Jeroboam. According to the Gnostic text Pistis Sophia, the head of one is found on the archon Yaldabaoth, sometimes identified as the Demiurge. In the valley of Timnah, several bees nested in the corpse of one of these creatures, where they made edible honey, as told in the book of Judges. This animal is often shown under images of the 24th tirthankar meditating, as it (*) symbolizes the Jain leader Mahavira. Saint Jerome removed a thorn from one of these creatures, and a winged one is the evangelical symbol of Saint Mark. Samson strangled one of these creatures, whose role as symbol for the tribe of Judah has led to its use by Rastafarians. For 10 points, name these carnivores which refused to harm the prophet Daniel after he was thrown in their den.", "answer": "lions", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>lions</u></b>", "acceptable": ["lions", "lions"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character in this book loves verbena-mint-tea and tries to steal a typewriter, only to find that he cannot lift it. An industrialist mentioned in this novel develops a tic in which he tries to lick his own ear after his factory is bankrupted by his stupid son, who becomes a famous soccer referee. In this novel, Gumercindo Tello threatens to castrate himself in court to prove himself innocent of rape. The narrator of this novel drives with (*) Javier and Pascual from town to town, trying to find a priest who will marry a minor. The stress of ten-hour days at Panamericana causes a character in this novel to mix up his creations and eventually kill them all off in a giant fire. For 10 points, name this novel about Pedro Camacho and the author's alter ego, who marries the title relative, a work by Mario Vargas Llosa. ", "answer": "Aunt Julia and the Scriptwriter [or La T\u00c3\u00ada Julia y el Escribidor] ", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Aunt Julia and the Scriptwriter</u></b> [or <b><u>La T\u00c3\u00ada Julia y el Escribidor</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Aunt Julia and the Scriptwriter", "Aunt Julia and the Scriptwriter", "La T\u00c3\u00ada Julia y el Escribidor"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Proteins can interact with these structures via TOG domains. A drug that prevents their formation cannot continue to be used in patients with foot drop and is 100% fatal if it gets into the spine; that drug is vincristine, which like vinblastine is a vinca alkaloid. A compound that prevents the growth of these structures is commonly used to treat gout, and that compound is also used to synchronize cells for karyotyping. Gamma ring complexes nucleate their growth, which alternate phases of (*) assembly and catastrophe in a process called \"dynamic instability\". Their monomers bind and hydrolyze GTP. Their growth is inhibited by colchicine and stabilized by taxol, and they form the mitotic spindle by connecting chromosomes to the centrosome. These structures are made of tubulin. For 10 points, name these components of the cytoskeleton that are bigger than intermediate filaments. ", "answer": "microtubules", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>microtubules</u></b>", "acceptable": ["microtubules", "microtubules"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}